<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-10-15T20:28:14-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id><title type="html">LuckEast</title><subtitle>Fudong's Personal Website.</subtitle><author><name>Fudong Wang</name></author><entry><title type="html">About me and my research</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/myself/2022/10/15/About-Me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="About me and my research" /><published>2022-10-15T01:50:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-15T01:50:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/myself/2022/10/15/About-Me</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/myself/2022/10/15/About-Me/">&lt;p&gt;My name is Fudong Wang. I am currently working as a postdoc at UCF (supervised by Alexander Tovbis). My dissertation mentor is Wen-Xiu Ma. My research interests include classical soliton theory ( inverse scattering, long-time asymptotics) and (currently) spectral theory of soliton/breather gases. Besides the integrable system, I am also interested in any fields related to the following keywords: Riemann-Hilbert problems, random matrices, orthogonal polynomial, probability theory, potential theory, asymptotic analysis, singular integral equations and approximation theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am dedicated to research in mathematical physics and applied analysis. In particular, I am interested in applying analytical tools to study nonlinear integrable PDEs and to understand the physics phenomenon behind those PDEs. The Korteweg–De Vries equation (KdV) and the focusing Nonlinear Schrödinger equation (fNLS) are two important examples among them. Both KdV and fNLS are considered as universal mathematical models describing physics phenomena of nonlinear waves. Thus, many applications can be found in many other fields such as oceanography, nonlinear optical, shallow water wave, and so on. My Ph.D study mainly focuses on the long-time asymptotics of a family of integrable PDEs using some recently developed asymptotics analysis techniques (namely, matrix Riemann-Hilbert problems, nonlinear steepest descent method,  $\bar\partial$-steepest descent method.). While during my postdoctoral period, I mainly consider the spectral theory arising in the study of KdV and fNLS soliton gas.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fudong Wang</name></author><category term="soliton gas" /><category term="fNLS" /><category term="soliton" /><summary type="html">My name is Fudong Wang. I am currently working as a postdoc at UCF (supervised by Alexander Tovbis). My dissertation mentor is Wen-Xiu Ma. My research interests include classical soliton theory ( inverse scattering, long-time asymptotics) and (currently) spectral theory of soliton/breather gases. Besides the integrable system, I am also interested in any fields related to the following keywords: Riemann-Hilbert problems, random matrices, orthogonal polynomial, probability theory, potential theory, asymptotic analysis, singular integral equations and approximation theory.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Projects</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2022/10/15/Proj/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Projects" /><published>2022-10-15T01:42:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-15T01:42:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2022/10/15/Proj</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2022/10/15/Proj/">&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;on-going-projects&quot;&gt;On-going Projects&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current research at UCF is concentrated on the spectral theory of certain nonlinear integrable PDEs (fNLS and KdV in particular). It is well-known that solitons and breathers (two types of special solutions) represent localized solutions to many integrable system. We are interested in studying the statistical ensembles of solitons/breathers, which are so-called &lt;b&gt;soliton/breather gases&lt;/b&gt;. The study of soliton/breather gases provides a possibility to understand one of the most intriguing phenomena of modern science - &lt;b&gt;turbulence in dynamical systems&lt;/b&gt;[see Za2009].
               &lt;br /&gt;
              In one project, we consider fNLS soliton/breather gas.  We derive average densities and fluxes for such gases by studying the thermodynamic limit of the fNLS finite gap solutions. One of the central objects in the spectral theory of soliton/breather gases is the nonlinear dispersion relation integral equation (NDR):
              &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;% &lt;![CDATA[
\begin{align*}
                \int_{\Gamma^+}
                \left[\log\left| \frac{w-\bar z}{w-z}\right|+ {\log\left|\frac{R_0(z)R_0(w)+z w -\delta_0^2}
                {R_0(\bar z)R_0(w)+\bar z w-\delta_0^2}\right|}\right]   u(w) d\lambda(w)
                +\sigma(z)u(z) &amp;= \Im R_0(z), \\
                 \int_{\Gamma^+}
                \left[\log\left| \frac{w-\bar z}{w-z}\right|+{\log\left|\frac{R_0(z)R_0(w)+ z w-\delta_0^2}
                {R_0(\bar z)R_0(w)+ \bar z w-\delta_0^2}\right|}\right] v(w) d\lambda(w)
                +\sigma(z)v(z) &amp;= - 2\Im[z R_0(z)],
                \end{align*} %]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where  $R_0(z)=\sqrt{z^2-\delta_0^2}$ with the branchcut $\gamma_0=[-\delta_0,\delta_0]\subset i\mathbb{R}$ being the exceptional (permanent) band, $\Gamma^+\subset \mathbb{C}^+\setminus \gamma_0$ is a compact,
             $z\in\Gamma^+$, $\sigma$ is a continuous non negative function on $\Gamma^+$
            and $\lambda$ is some reference measure (arclength measure if $\Gamma^+$ is a contour, area measure if $\Gamma^+$ is a 2D region) on $\Gamma^+$ that
            reflects the density of accumulating in the thermodynamic limit
            bands. In the case of $\delta_0=0$ the fNLS breather gas reduces to the
            fNLS soliton gas with the NDR given by removing the blue parts in the breather NDR. The solution $u(z)$ to the first NDR (assuming the existence) is called density of states, which plays a fundamental role in our project. With the help of &lt;b&gt;finite-gap theory&lt;/b&gt;, we established the following results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Computing the &lt;strong&gt;averaged conserved quantities&lt;/strong&gt; (i.e., the densities and fluxes) under thermodynamic limit.
    For example, in the soliton gas case, the averaged densities can be computed by the following elegant formula:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;\begin{align*}
I_m =2\int_{\Gamma^+}u(\zeta)\Im \zeta^m d\lambda(\zeta),
\end{align*}&lt;/script&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;where  $u$ is the density of states, and $I_m$ denotes the averaged density that is associate with the coefficient of the expansion of quasimomentum differential:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;\begin{align*}
dp=\left(1-\sum_{m=1}^\infty\frac{I_m}{z^{m+1}}\right)dz.
\end{align*}&lt;/script&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;In the paper [TW2022], we present the formulae of computing averaged densities for fNLS breather gases. The results provide certain statistical properties of the soliton/breather ensembles.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Motivated by some formal WKB analysis&lt;/b&gt; results on the periodic Zakharov-Shabat operator, we solve the first NDR  equation explicitly in both breather and soliton gas limit cases. We call them &lt;b&gt;periodic gases&lt;/b&gt;.
 In the periodic gases case, the density of state is represented by the following formula:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;u(z)= \frac{|  z|}{\pi L}\int_{0}^{q^{-1}(|  z|)}\frac{dx} {\sqrt{q^2(x)+  z^2}},\quad   z\in\Gamma^+,&lt;/script&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;where $q(x)$ is some periodic function as the potential in the Zakharov-Shabat operator. One surprising result is that $u$ is proportional to the density function of the centers of the bands (the spectra of the periodic Zakharov-Shabat operator).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We &lt;b&gt;established some fundamental error estimates&lt;/b&gt; in the thermodynamic-type limit.
 Specifically speaking, we give the large N leading behavior of certain differentials defined on the genus 2N Riemann surface. And those error estimates provide a rigorous mathematical foundation of deriving the NDR equations as well as of computing the averaged conserved quantities. Our results constitute another step towards the mathematical foundation for the spectral theory of fNLS soliton and breather gases that appeared in work of G. El and A. Tovbis\cite{ET2020}.[&lt;b&gt;This project is joint work with Alexander Tovbis.&lt;/b&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;past-projects&quot;&gt;Past Projects&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main object of my dissertation research is the AKNS hierarchy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;% &lt;![CDATA[
\begin{align*}
% \label{lax pair AKNS}
  \psi_x=\begin{pmatrix}
  iz&amp; p(x,t)\\
  q(x,t)&amp; -iz
  \end{pmatrix}\psi,\quad \psi_t=\sum_{j=1}^nV(p,q)z^j,
\end{align*} %]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where $\psi(z;x,t)\in GL(2;\mathbb{C};\mathbb{R},\mathbb{R}_+)$. We are mainly interested in studying the long-time ($t\rightarrow\infty$) behaviors of the potential $p(x,t)$ in different sectors of the $(x,t)$ plane. Through Riemann-Hilbert formulations (one modern way of formulating inverse scattering problems), we then apply so-called $\bar\partial$-steepest descent method (a variant of the famous Deift-Zhou’s nonlinear steepest descent method) to derive the explicit asymptotics in three regions (namely, fast decaying region, Painlevé region, fast oscillating region) in the $(x,t)$ plane. And in each region, the error estimates are also provided. In particular, in the Painlevé region, the asymptotic solutions to the mKdV hierarchy (the odd part of AKNS hierarchy) are associated to the Painlevé II hierarchy. The details are presented in this paper by Ma and Myself.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/NewPhysicalDroplet2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Droplet&quot; style=&quot;width:500px;height:400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Besides the main project, I also want to mention a side project which emphasizes on complex analysis. Consider a droplet in a electric field (as presented by a complex potential $g$), the equilibrium state of the droplet results in the following free-boundary problem satisfied on the boundary (to be determined):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;\begin{equation*}
      F(z)=\int^z (g'(s))^2 ds = p \bar{z} + i \tau \dot{\bar{z}},
    \end{equation*}&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where “dot” here represents the derivative with respect to arc length, and for  positive constants $p$
(representing the strength of the pressure force), $\tau$ (representing the strength of the
force due to surface tension). The task is to find solutions to the free boundary problem, i.e., find $z=z(s)$, s is in the unit disc,  and $F(z)$ satisfying the stated equation as well as  the physical condition that $\sqrt{F’(z)}$ is single-valued. Our result provides a family of solutions (so-called physical  droplets, see the Figure in the middle, where a family of physical droplets is presented.). More details are presented in the paper by Hayford and myself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fudong Wang</name></author><category term="soliton gas" /><category term="fNLS" /><category term="soliton" /><summary type="html">On-going Projects My current research at UCF is concentrated on the spectral theory of certain nonlinear integrable PDEs (fNLS and KdV in particular). It is well-known that solitons and breathers (two types of special solutions) represent localized solutions to many integrable system. We are interested in studying the statistical ensembles of solitons/breathers, which are so-called soliton/breather gases. The study of soliton/breather gases provides a possibility to understand one of the most intriguing phenomena of modern science - turbulence in dynamical systems[see Za2009]. In one project, we consider fNLS soliton/breather gas. We derive average densities and fluxes for such gases by studying the thermodynamic limit of the fNLS finite gap solutions. One of the central objects in the spectral theory of soliton/breather gases is the nonlinear dispersion relation integral equation (NDR):</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Publications</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/publications/2022/10/15/Publications/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Publications" /><published>2022-10-15T01:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-15T01:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/publications/2022/10/15/Publications</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/publications/2022/10/15/Publications/">&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Recent developments in spectral theory of the focusing NLS soliton and breather gases: the thermodynamic limit of average densities, fluxes and certain meromorphic differentials; periodic gases, &lt;b&gt;Journal of Physics A &lt;/b&gt;, 2022. (with Alexander Tovbis)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A $\bar\partial$-Steepest Descent Method for Oscillatory Riemann–Hilbert Problems, &lt;b&gt;Journal of Nonlinear Science&lt;/b&gt;, 2022. (with Wen-Xiu Ma)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A Note on Electrified Droplets,&lt;b&gt; Computational Methods and Function Theory&lt;/b&gt;, 2021.(with Nathan
     Hayford)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Inverse scattering transforms for non-local reverse-space matrix non-linear Schrödinger equations, &lt;b&gt;European Journal of Applied Mathematics&lt;/b&gt;, 2021. (with Wen-Xiu Ma, Yehui Huang)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Inverse scattering transforms and soliton solutions of nonlocal reverse-space nonlinear Schrödinger hierarchies, &lt;b&gt;Studies in Applied Mathematics&lt;/b&gt;, 2020. (with Wen-Xiu Ma, Yehui Huang)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Lump solutions to nonlinear PDEs involving Hirota derivative $D^2_tD_xD_y$, &lt;b&gt;Modern Physics Letters B&lt;/b&gt;, 2020. (with Wen-Xiu Ma)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Fudong Wang</name></author><category term="soliton gas" /><category term="fNLS" /><category term="soliton" /><summary type="html">Recent developments in spectral theory of the focusing NLS soliton and breather gases: the thermodynamic limit of average densities, fluxes and certain meromorphic differentials; periodic gases, Journal of Physics A , 2022. (with Alexander Tovbis)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MathJax with Jekyll</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/opinion/2014/02/16/Mathjax-with-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MathJax with Jekyll" /><published>2014-02-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2014-02-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/opinion/2014/02/16/Mathjax-with-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/opinion/2014/02/16/Mathjax-with-jekyll/">&lt;p&gt;One of the rewards of switching my website to &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is the
ability to support &lt;strong&gt;MathJax&lt;/strong&gt;, which means I can write LaTeX-like equations that get
nicely displayed in a web browser, like this one \( \sqrt{\frac{n!}{k!(n-k)!}} \) or
this one \( x^2 + y^2 = r^2 \). $h^3$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;centered&quot; src=&quot;https://www.mathjax.org/badge/mj-logo.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-mathjax&quot;&gt;What’s MathJax?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you check MathJax website &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mathjax.org/&quot;&gt;(www.mathjax.org)&lt;/a&gt; you’ll see
that it &lt;em&gt;is an open source JavaScript display engine for mathematics that works in all
browsers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-implement-mathjax-with-jekyll&quot;&gt;How to implement MathJax with Jekyll&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed the instructions described by Dason Kurkiewicz for
&lt;a href=&quot;http://dasonk.github.io/blog/2012/10/09/Using-Jekyll-and-Mathjax/&quot;&gt;using Jekyll and Mathjax&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some important details. I had to modify the Ruby library for Markdown in
my &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; file. Now I’m using redcarpet so the corresponding line in the
configuration file is: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;markdown: redcarpet&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To load the MathJax javascript, I added the following lines in my layout &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;post.html&lt;/code&gt;
(located in my folder &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_layouts&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot; data-lang=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;text/javascript&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;src&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;http://cdn.mathjax.org/mathjax/latest/MathJax.js?config=TeX-AMS-MML_HTMLorMML&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you can choose a different file location in your jekyll layouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that by default, the &lt;strong&gt;tex2jax&lt;/strong&gt; preprocessor defines the
LaTeX math delimiters, which are &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\\(...\\)&lt;/code&gt; for in-line math, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\\[...\\]&lt;/code&gt; for
displayed equations. It also defines the TeX delimiters &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$$...$$&lt;/code&gt; for displayed
equations, but it does not define &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$...$&lt;/code&gt; as in-line math delimiters. To enable in-line math delimiter with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$...$&lt;/code&gt;, please use the following configuration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot; data-lang=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;text/x-mathjax-config&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;MathJax.Hub.Config&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;({&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tex2jax&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;inlineMath&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'$'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'$'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'\\('&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'\\)'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;processEscapes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;src&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;https://cdn.mathjax.org/mathjax/latest/MathJax.js?config=TeX-AMS-MML_HTMLorMML&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;text/javascript&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-couple-of-examples&quot;&gt;A Couple of Examples&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a short list of examples. To know more about the details behind MathJax, you can
always checked the provided documentation available at
&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.mathjax.org/en/latest/&quot;&gt;http://docs.mathjax.org/en/latest/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s try a first example. Here’s a dummy equation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;a^2 + b^2 = c^2&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you write such expression? Very simple: using &lt;strong&gt;double dollar&lt;/strong&gt; signs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot; data-lang=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;^&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;^&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;^&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To display inline math use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\\( ... \\)&lt;/code&gt; like this &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\\( sin(x^2) \\)&lt;/code&gt; which gets
rendered as \( sin(x^2) \)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s another example using type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\mathsf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot; data-lang=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;mathsf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;PCs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;mathsf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Loadings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which gets displayed as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;\mathsf{Data = PCs} \times \mathsf{Loadings}&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or even better:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot; data-lang=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;\\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;X&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Z&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;P&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;^&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;mathsf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;\\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;is displayed as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\[ \mathbf{X} = \mathbf{Z} \mathbf{P^\mathsf{T}} \]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to use subscripts like this \( \mathbf{X}_{n,p} \) you need to scape the
underscores with a backslash like so &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\mathbf{X}\_{n,p}&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot; data-lang=&quot;r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;X&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;\_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;\_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;B&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;\_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;will be displayed as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\[ \mathbf{X}_{n,p} = \mathbf{A}_{n,k} \mathbf{B}_{k,p} \]&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fudong Wang</name></author><category term="resources" /><category term="jekyll" /><summary type="html">One of the rewards of switching my website to Jekyll is the ability to support MathJax, which means I can write LaTeX-like equations that get nicely displayed in a web browser, like this one \( \sqrt{\frac{n!}{k!(n-k)!}} \) or this one \( x^2 + y^2 = r^2 \). $h^3$</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://gastonsanchez.com/images/blog/mathjax_logo.png" /></entry></feed>